# Michael Mazzarella

Pacific Palisades, CA 90272 | michael\_mazzarella@hotmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/Michaelm999 | Portfolio: https://michaelm999.github.io/Portfolio/ |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-mazzarella-46336973/

#### **Summary:**

I am a Southern California-based Web Developer, with experience working in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap and React. I have been using these experiences to produce several online apps that showcase my creativity and imagination. Before becoming a developer, I worked for a tech startup on a brand-new app. I was in charge of managing and editing the app's content, and came to understand the multitude of challenges and opportunities present in the tech world. I'm currently working on a new app called QuestionThis, a Q&A application using React, Express, MongoDB and CSS.

### **Technical Skills**

• Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby

• Web Application Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Express, Node, React.js

• Front-end-Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS

• Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

• Version Control: Git/GitHub

### **Projects:**

#### 1. Riddle Me This

- A multiple-choice puzzle game designed for two players and developed in three days.
- Made with HTML, CSS, JS and ¡Query.

### 2. FanLife

- An application created in four days, FanLife allows users to comment and favorite their favorite shows and movies. This is a full CRUD application that utilizes a postgreSQL database and communicates with multiple models.
- Developed with Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, CSS and SQL.

#### 3. MovieTroll

- MovieTroll is an application for movie critique and review. Using our API, users are allowed to visit and view the movie database and look at comments before logging in. Once they are signed in, they're allowed to upload movie and save it to the home page.
- This application was developed as a group. I was in charge of creating the comment section, as well as the CSS/Bootstrap styling.
- Developed on Node, Express, MongoDB, HTML, and CSS.

#### 4. QuestionThis

- QuestionThis is the latest question and answer application on the web. On this application, people are able to post questions, edit questions, delete questions, and most importantly, answer questions. It utilizes a MongoDB that I had created.
- This app was made out of HTML, React.js, Express, MongoDB, and Node.js.

# **Education**

# University of San Diego, B.A.

2013

Cum Laude

Major: English

Minor: Sociology

# **University of San Diego – Summer Business Institute**

2013

Awarded with Distinction

### **Professional History:**

# **Development Researcher**

2017-Present

In One Instant

- Developed detailed contact & mailing list of schools and individuals for outreach
- Cultivated and managed list of foundations for future funding.

# **Data/Content Manager**

2015 - 2017

Rivo

- Collect and edit content for the development of a new calendar app.
- Develop, update, and maintain multiple calendars simultaneously for the app.
- Write and edit descriptions and general content for the app.
- Maintain Company's twitter account.
- Engaged in guerilla marketing.
- Use bitly to attract people to our website.

### **Grant Writer/Research Intern**

2015 - 2016

Kidsave

- Research new funding opportunities for their summer programs.
- Write grants & LOIs for foundations to allow the organization to expand its programs.
- Organized Grants, records, and other materials used for fundraising and reporting.